<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://4till2.com</id>
    <title>4till2 site</title>
    <updated>2022-04-24T17:23:24.658Z</updated>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <author>
        <name>4till2</name>
        <email>yo@4till2.com</email>
        <uri>https://twitter.com/4till2</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://4till2.com"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://4till2.com/rss/atom.xml"/>
    <logo>https://4till2.com/logo.svg</logo>
    <icon>https://4till2.com/favicon.png</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2022, 4till2</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Built This Site]]></title>
        <id>https://4till2.com/words/why-this-site</id>
        <link href="https://4till2.com/words/why-this-site"/>
        <updated>2022-04-21T18:35:45.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>For my forthcoming trip I really wanted to balance the desire to share with that of being untethered.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Not too long ago I thought to myself "I should hike the Pacific Crest Trail". All 2662 miles (4284 km) of it. In not too
long I will try. Along the way I'm bound for some epic adventures. I'd love for a way to take my family and friends
along for the journey, digitally that is. There's only one problem. I don't like social media.</p>
<p>I could probably write an
essay arguing why but as the great Kevin Malone once said "why say lot word when few do trick". Social media sucks. It
sucks for the addictive features, it sucks for the self-confidence busters, it sucks for the data lock ins, it sucks for
the privacy invasions, it sucks for the platform restrictions, it sucks for the hate fueled conversations, and it sucks
for the information bubbles. But everyone already knows these reasons and figure them an alright price to pay for dank
meme wars. I get it. There are as many if not more upsides than downsides. But there's a reason social media sucks that
maybe isn't mentioned as frequently as the others. Social media lacks context.</p>
<p>Everything shared on social media is a "
moment". A single photo, story, video, tweet, or even link are all shared in isolation from one another. Yet that's not
how things actually rarely are. Even a picture of an amazing vacation is greater in context to the previous weeks boring
desk job. Yet these contextual bits of information are seriously lacking from any popular platform. Ephemeral moments
competing for our fleeting attention. And all we're left with are particles of thoughts, experiences, and ideas.</p>
<p>There are certainly good reasons to use these platforms, and I probably will, but for my mental health and intellectual
curiosity they rarely suffice. In regular life I do just fine as a passive lurker but for my forthcoming trip I really
wanted to find a way to balance the desire to share with that of being untethered. A simple blog or public photo album
would be an alright start but still too restrictive. I want to take my family and friends on the
journey with me. Have them seen the things I'm seeing, understand the challenges ahead and behind, and get to peek into
the day to day of their PCT thru-hiker. They should be able to ask how many miles did I walk today? What was the
weather? Where did I start and finish? Who did I meet? What portion of the trail did I tackle? What night camping was
it? What views did I wake up to? How was all this different from yesterday, or two weeks ago? Where will I be tomorrow
or two weeks from now? All of these questions are real elements of an experience full of continual context not easily broken down into one off data, tweets, images, or stories.</p>
<p>My mission with this website is to create a place to share the journey in its continuum. Start to finish, in real time, with all the possible context of the experience itself. So
I put together this site, a collection of realtime content from my journey, shared automatically in the background to my
regular activities. 'Waypoints' are fetched from my Garmin tracker, 'Photos' from a Google Photos album, 'Words' my
notes app, and 'Logs' the result of a Shortcut on my iPhone. It took a few trys to get right, and I fully anticipate
Uncle Murphy to laugh at all efforts to prevent an implosion on day 1, but for now I'm glad about the results and
excited to experiment with this form of journaling from the trail!</p>
<p>Todo: Organize a more in depth explanation of the technical implementations.</p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>4till2</name>
            <email>yo@4till2.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/4till2</uri>
        </author>
        <contributor>
            <name>4till2</name>
            <email>yo@4till2.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/4till2</uri>
        </contributor>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resources for Hiking The Pacific Crest Trail]]></title>
        <id>https://4till2.com/words/pct-resources</id>
        <link href="https://4till2.com/words/pct-resources"/>
        <updated>2022-04-21T17:47:45.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some resources I collected while researching thru-hiking the Pacific Crest Trail. Some are good for pre trip others I intend
to use on trail.</p>
<h2>Pre Trail</h2>
<p><strong>General Info</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.pcta.org">Official PCT site</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PacificCrestTrail/">Pct Subreddit</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Maps</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/viewer?mid=1UtogyvQzegPXZYLARMCTwckZTRxIOOLf&#x26;ll=41.34499145337969%2C-119.83531350000001&#x26;z=5">Google Map Version</a></li>
<li><a href="https://arcg.is/1vT1ui0">PCTA Interactive Map</a> (Lots of layers to play around with)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Gps Data and Trail Notes</strong>
I used these to learn more about what lies ahead. Practically all apps and maps I came across reference the "Halfmile" field data.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://pctmap.net/gps/">Halfmile GPX data</a></li>
<li><a href="https://pctmap.net/trail-notes/">Halfmile Trail Notes</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.arcgis.com/home/search.html?q=owner%3A%22gkeily_PCTA%22&#x26;restrict=false&#x26;sortOrder=desc&#x26;sortField=relevance#content">Awesome collection of Map layers</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Planning</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.halfwayanywhere.com/pacific-crest-trail/">Gear, Surveys, Blog</a> (Pretty sweet blog run by a guy named Mac)</li>
<li><a href="https://pctplanner.com">pctplanner.com</a> (I haven't actually tried this site.)</li>
<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/u/0/d/1DsLpp9lEXGZTKWVMyA3eNTeN4NHTSGGAwln1yoWI0Cw/htmlview#">Hiker Food Database</a> (from the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCflIoVkAjQnyAwDKFmhRDDw">GearSkeptic</a> on YouTube)</li>
</ul>
<h2>On Trail</h2>
<p><strong>Getting to the trail</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://pctsouthernterminusshuttle.com/https/book-your-ride">Shuttle Service</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Water Report</strong>
A community led initiative to track the water status along the trail.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://pctwater.com">https://pctwater.com</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/viewer?mid=1UtogyvQzegPXZYLARMCTwckZTRxIOOLf&#x26;ll=41.34499145337969%2C-119.83531350000001&#x26;z=5">Google Map Version</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jithware/mappoff">Android App (experimental)</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mapping</strong>
I will use a mix of custom map printouts, and digital data imports from the above resources.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gaiagps.com">Gaia App</a> (I imported the kml/gpx data from above resources)</li>
<li><a href="https://faroutguides.com">FarOut</a> (Apparently very popular on trail for staying in the know)</li>
<li><a href="https://explore.garmin.com">Garmin</a> (Using an InReach2 for waypoint tracking. Also with imported layers.)</li>
<li><a href="/resources/halfmiles-pct-notes-all-4-page.html">All Halfmile Notes Minified</a> (I made this easy 2 page print out for lightweight and quick offline info.)</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>4till2</name>
            <email>yo@4till2.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/4till2</uri>
        </author>
        <contributor>
            <name>4till2</name>
            <email>yo@4till2.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/4till2</uri>
        </contributor>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20220328173055]]></title>
        <id>https://4till2.com/logs/20220328173055</id>
        <link href="https://4till2.com/logs/20220328173055"/>
        <updated>2022-04-21T18:10:45.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I will try to share logs like this daily. The metadata is autofilled by a shortcut on my iphone. Other nonsense from the day might land here to. All written content for this site is taken on a notes app on my phone or computer, synced with github, fetched by this site, and displayed accordingly.</p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>4till2</name>
            <email>yo@4till2.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/4till2</uri>
        </author>
        <contributor>
            <name>4till2</name>
            <email>yo@4till2.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/4till2</uri>
        </contributor>
    </entry>
</feed>